<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nod&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nod&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:51:40 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Monthly Patch 2025.01</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/the-monthly-patch-2025.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:51:40 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/the-monthly-patch-2025.01/</guid>
      <description>The Monthly Patch 2025.01 Welcome to The Monthly Patch, a new blog series where I document my cybersecurity journey, both personal and professional. My goal with this blog is twofold:&#xA;To serve as a motivational tool—tracking my progress and pushing myself to continuously improve. To provide a transparent record of my learning journey—allowing potential employers and like-minded professionals to see my dedication to cybersecurity growth. Each month, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover my progress, learning experiences, projects, and future goals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m Jarrod, but most folks know me as Nod. I&amp;rsquo;m a tech enthusiast located in Australia with over ten years of experience in the telecommunications industry and a dedicated cybersecurity professional. My passion for cybersecurity stems from my curiosity and a strong desire to protect our digital world.&#xA;My Cybersecurity Journey After a decade in telecommunications, where I built a solid foundation in networking, IT support, and troubleshooting, I made the leap into cybersecurity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTF Blue THM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/ctf-blue-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:42:43 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/ctf-blue-thm/</guid>
      <description>TryHackMe CTF: Blue Room Writeup&#xA;https://tryhackme.com/r/room/blue&#xA;Room Information&#xA;This room was created by ben and DarkStar7471, members of the TryHackMe community. This is my second CTF, and I will document my thought process and actions as I go through the challenges.&#xA;Initial Scanning&#xA;I started by running an Nmap scan on the target IP address:&#xA;sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -T4 -vv 10.10.216.233 The Nmap scan revealed several open ports:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/hello-world./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:09:52 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/hello-world./</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! This initial post serves as a test to ensure everything is functioning correctly. Stay tuned for more updates and content.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
